## COREY JACKSON

SUDBURY, ONTARIO • 705-885-5432 • cjaxsn@gmail.com • https://coreyjackson.tech

#### **PROFILE**

A dynamic senior IT professional with over 20 years experience in information technology with focuses in management, project management, security, architecture, networking, systems analysis, integration, automation, development, quality assurance, & support in both private and public sectors.

#### SOFT SKILLS

- Leadership, team building, decision making, mentoring, motivational, negotiation, and presentation skills
- Innovative, creative, responsible, cooperative, hard working, versatile, flexible, and adaptable
- Possess strong organizational, time management, conflict management, and analytical thinking skills
- Written and oral communication skills in English and French languages

#### TECHNICAL / HARD SKILLS

Management: Strategic planning, department & product management, budgeting, performance mgmt.

Project Management: Agile, Waterfall, Scrum, Scheduling, Prioritization, JIRA, MS Project, Primavera

Architecture: TOGAF, SDLC, process mapping, data modeling, service oriented architecture (SOA)

Security: Vulnerability Management, Penetration Testing, Ethical Hacking, System Harderning, Information Security, Secure Application Development, Password Management, NIST 800-x, ISO 27001, PCI DSS, 2FA/MFA/U2F, OAuth, SSO, SAML, SSL/TLS, AES, PGP, CORS, CSRF, XSS, Email and Web Security Gateways, DLP, DMARC, Kali Linux, FileAudit Plus, Netwrix, Nmap, Nessus, Metasploit, Nikto

Cloud & Server Computing: IaaS, PaaS, Saas, AWS, Azure, Digital Ocean, Scale, VMWare, VirtualBox

DevOps: Bamboo, BitBucket, Git, SourceTree, TortoiseGit, Bash, Shell, PowerShell, Kubernetes

**Development Languages/Technologies:** API's, Python, JSON, ASP.NET, JSP, PHP, Perl, CSS, HTML, XML, AJAX, Bootstrap, jQuery, React, AngularJS, node.js, Java, JavaScript, Groovy, C#, Git, SPA, PWA

#### Data Applications/Technologies:

NoSQL - CouchDB, PouchDB, IndexedDB, MongoDB

RDBMS - MS SQL Server, MariaDB, MySQL, Oracle, SQLLite, ADO, DAO, ODBC, OLEDB, SQL Data historians/products: AspenTech Setcim, OSISoft PI, PI-ACE, PI-AF, PI Batch, PI Coresight, PI-PE, DataLink, PI Manual Logger, ProcessBook, PI WebParts, Totalizers

OT/Process Control: SCADA, DCS, InFusion, Wonderware, Foxboro, PLCs, RSView, HMI's

**Networking:** WAN,LAN,VLAN,MESH,UTM,ASA,Firewalls,Routers,Gateways,Switches,Hubs,Bridges, Access Points, Print Servers, Proxies,VPN,DHCP,DNS,WINS,TCP/IP,IPSEC,IPS/IDS,ACLs,QoS, SSH, STP, NTP, SNMP, RADIUS, SIP, VOIP, SIEM, Satellite and Cellular comm, Cabling (CAT5/6), IP Cameras,FreePBX, SolSwitch, wireless network optimization, interior and exterior network installation

Networking Tools: inSSIDer, NetSpot, NetLimiter, PTRG, PuTTY, Nmap, Wireshark, tcpdump, iPerf Web Servers and Remote Tools: Apache, NGINX, IIS, Tomcat, Team Viewer, Anydesk, VNC, RDP Operating Systems: Linux, Unix, Mac OS, iOS, Android, Windows 3.xx-10/Server 2000-2016, VMS, DOS Design/Estimating: UML, ERD, DFD, Visio, Draw.io, AutoCAD, Revit, SketchUp, Accubid, WinEst Reporting: ActiveReports, Business Objects, Crystal Reports, Pentaho, Power BI, SSRS, SharePoint

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Sofvie Inc. 2019-2020

#### **Product & Service Supervisor**

- Managed direct reports in various roles of product development
- Supervised direct reports in the support and service of customers and internal staff
- Supervised direct reports in continuous delivery and integration of products (DevOps)
- Managed best practices and standards in the product development of a secure risk management system
- Managed the project development plan and resources
- Lead product quality assurance and implementation of automated testing framework

COREY JACKSON 2

# TESC Contracting Company Ltd. & SWSE Athletic Teams IT Manager

2015-2019

- Managed comprehensive IT portfolio and IT projects with direct reports and 3<sup>rd</sup> party resources
- Managed an IT helpdesk for 200 users utilizing ITIL framework for incident and problem management
- Implemented cost and time saving solutions, new technologies, policies, procedures, and standards
- Reduced costs in IT and various areas of the business
- Managed IT infrastructure (servers, storage, backups, security systems), licenses, and vendor contracts
- Managed the implementation of corporate security based initiatives:
  - File, email, and application auditing, mobile device management (MDM) and data loss prevention (DLP) on COPE and BYOD devices, information classification & security, password management, email and web security gateways, network intrusion and prevention systems, website security and monitoring, anti-virus/malware/ransomware, security awareness training, software license compliancy,IoT platform enabling keyless entry with auditing, surveillance systems, security operations centre (SOC), systems security, secure authentication, disaster recovery, created maintained corporate policies including acceptable use policy, device policies, cyber security policy, file storage policy
- Assisted in the implementation of a PCI DSS compliant point of sale system at the Sudbury arena
- Managed the implementation of several key IT projects:
  - Digital transformation, global enterprise wireless network, standard video conferencing and collaboration system, inventory management systems (IT and specific business areas), safety management information system, company intranet, global VoIP system

Vale Canada Limited 2009-2015

### IT Subject Matter Expert / IT Project Manager

- Managed a team of developers including project budgets, schedules and training development
- Implemented best practices, standards, and product roadmaps for areas of expertise
- Managed the implementation of many IT projects such as: computerized mould tracking system, redundant data collection system from the Smelter process control network to business network, division wide production information reporting system (KPI's and real-time information), computerized systems for the atmospheric emissions reduction (AER) program, smelting converter aisle monitoring system, migration of Setcim data historian to OSISoft PI historian, applications using OSISoft technologies
- Product lead on SAP Manufacturing Integration and Intelligence (MII)

Vale Canada Limited 2005-2009

#### Process Systems Analyst

- Design, develop, test, deliver and support information and process control systems
- Implemented new technologies into business applications, business requirements analysis/translation
- Lead IT contractors and projects, served as mentor to colleagues

#### **EDUCATION**

Georgian College (Diploma, 3 Year Computer Programmer/Analyst Co-op w/ Honours) 1999-2002

Lo-Ellen Park Secondary School (Ontario Secondary School Diploma w/Honours) 1994-1999

#### LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

CompTIA Project+, CompTIA	08/2020
CompTIA PenTest+, CompTIA	09/2020
CompTIA Security+, CompTIA	08/2020
Effective Leadership Development, LMI Canada	03/2016
Ontario Drivers License (Class G)	02/1998